Ashley Phillips

Website: www.nodeocrat.com

Email: ashley.phillips@nodeocrat.com

Mobile: 07783 988250

PROFILE

SUMMARY

Adaptable developer with experience in big data real-time analytics, banking software, web app development and high stress environments.

Experienced with writing software in a range of programming languages and frameworks across the full stack and software life cycle with a thorough understanding of the need for careful design and best practices after having worked with plenty of well designed and poorly designed software.

EDUCATION

University of Brighton 2011 - 2014 BSc Mathematics 2:1

SKILLS

KEY SKILLS

<u>Front-end</u>: Javascript (ES6), React, Flux/Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Web Components <u>Back-end</u>: Node.js, Express, Passport, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, WebSockets, SQL & NoSOL

Testing: TDD, BDD, Mocha, Cucumber

DevOps/Other: AWS, Webpack & Babel, Git, Linux, NPM, Ansible, Travis,

Documenting APIs

OTHER RELEVANT SKILLS

Front-end: AngularDart, Qt

Back-end: C++

DevOps/Other: Java, Google Dart, SubVersion, nginx

MISCELLANEOUS

Redmine, JIRA, TDD, Scrum, Software design patterns & algorithm design, SOLID principles, Mathematical modelling, statistical analysis and forecasting

PAST EMPLOYMENT

Dev2Rights, London. July 2017 - November 2017

JavaScript (ES6), Node.js, React, Redux, AWS (Lambda, EC2, API Gateway, S3, RDB, CloudFront, CloudWatch, IAM, JavaScript SDK), HTML5, CSS3, Bash, Git, PostgreSQL, Travis, Ansible, JIRA

A development agency working on a recruitment app (https://hiupapp.com). Full-stack role from AWS & Ansible through to front-end React & Redux. Duties included mainly developing with React/Redux and Node.js to develop new front-end features

and lambda's (AWS), and enhancing existing ones, while heavily interacting with & configuring the other AWS features mentioned and working alongside Ansible for build automation (managed by the devops team). Was given a high level of independence and authority over the software.

Software Developer at Ancoa, London. Feb 2015 - May 2016

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Dart, AngularDart, C++, Qt framework, Dart, AngularDart, Linux, Git, PostgreSQL, redmine

Ancoa is a company which provides a platform to detect fraudulent behaviour in markets.

Joined the company when it was a still a startup so was able to contribute to all areas of the system; the core of the system, algorithms plugins to detect suspicious behaviour, data-integration, database management, linux build system, desktop and web front-end, client APIs and some client-facing tasks and attendance of Fintech events. Joined the web team full-time for last 5 months there.

Graduate Developer at Sword APAK, Bristol July 2014 - Feb 2015.

C++, .NET framework, SQL Server, JIRA

Sword Apak Banking Division provides a banking system used by smaller banks which combines all systems of traditional banking platforms into one agile system.

Introduced to the world of large scale software development. Learnt many new concepts. Worked closely with Business Analysts to enhance and develop new features.

June 2016 - June 2017.

After developing an interest for web development at Ancoa, I decided web development is a route I wanted to carry on going down, but was unhappy with the technologies used at Ancoa so took a break and discovered precisely which area of web development interested me the most after travelling for most of the summer. I experienced a range of technologies across the stack via online courses/tutorials, and projects with technologies including Node.js, React.js, Redux, AngularJS 2, MongoDB, ES6, AWS, Express, Passport, Webpack.

PERSONAL PROJECTS (https://www.nodeocrat.com/projects)

Client-server Room package

ES6, Node, WebSockets

My latest project, the Room package is designed to be used whenever there are multiple clients communicating with each other via a central server, with otherwise complex functionality made much easier to implement. Summary, samples, tutorial, git repo & API Docs: https://www.nodeocrat.com/projects/Room

Social App

ES6, Node, React, Redux, Socket.io, Express.js, CSS3, HTML5

A lobby with a chat room which has been integrated with the 'loopless game server' project mentioned below. Players can choose to create new instances of this game, or join one. This project involves advanced usage of data structures and design patterns with the aforementioned technologies. This project was what inspired me to write the Room package, and has itself been re-written to use the Room package.

<u>Git repository</u>

Client: https://github.com/Nodeocrat/client/tree/redux/react-app-

dev/src/components/Projects/NodeSocial

Server: https://github.com/Nodeocrat/backend/tree/redux/NodeSocial

Loopless game-server (nodeocrat.com/projects/GameProj)

ES6, Socket.IO, Node.js, HTML Canvas

Multiplayer game experiment with JS and Node for the backend with Socket.IO. Built using JavaScript with no other third party libraries; The back-end runs on a loopless game-server and is completely event driven, with collisions and positions only being calculated as and when they need to, rather than 30 times per seconds (as is usually the case), which greatly reduces server load. Multiple players can log in and shoot at each other and shrink/enlarge in size. Socket.IO has since been abandoned in favor of regular WebSockets (provided by Room package).

Personal website

ES6, React, Redux, Handlebars, AWS, Linux, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, passport (local, google, facebook strategies), Socket.io, bcrypt, Nginx

Website has had 3 re-writes. First version used vanilla JS with handlebars. Second version was written using React with the third version with React + Redux.

Git repository

Client: https://github.com/Nodeocrat/client/tree/redux/react-app-dev

Server: https://github.com/Nodeocrat/backend/tree/redux

Auslander-Parter Algorithm (nodeocrat.com/projects/ApAlg)

lava, Algorithm design

Software which demonstrates various Graph Theory algorithms written in Java, with the ability to draw your own graphs to be used as input to perform your chosen algorithm on.

Git repository

https://github.com/Nodeocrat/Graph-Theory-Algorithms/blob/master/src/Algorithms/AuslanderParter.java

REFERENCES

References provided on request. I can provide references for Dev2Rights, Ancoa, Sword APAK and University of Brighton.